ROHAN KINGAN

Senior engineer at General Dynamics Electric Boat with experience in system design, cybersecurity design, documentation, and networking. I have a passion for system level architecture that is elegant, extensible, and maintainable.



http://kingan.me http://linkedin.com/in/rdk1207 ☐ rdk1207@gmail.com

Work Experience

<u>Senior Systems Engineer</u> (January 2018 – Present) <u>General Dynamics Electric Boat – New London, CT</u>

- Updated ship subsystem specification to include COLUMBIA and VIRGINIA Block V Payload Module functionality.
- Responsible for flow-down of system level requirements to hardware, software, and test teams.
- Led hardware, software, and arrangement efforts to upgrade weapons platform touch panels to HD hardware variants.
- Developed static web application and documentation for generating tailored deliverables from requirement database exports.
- Provided engineering data package to designers to create/modify system-level technical drawings.
- Collaborated with engineers on next generation fiber inter/intra-subsystem weapons network topology.
- Evaluated Submarine Warfare Federated Tactical Systems feature requests for scope, feasibility, schedule impact, and scope.
- Integrated new cybersecurity features and requirements to subsystem TI/APB baseline.
- Conducted cybersecurity scans on baseline (fleetdeployed) configurations.

<u>Software Engineer Intern</u> (May 2015 – September 2015) **UpChannel – Newark, NJ**

- Developed back-end API (NodeJS / MongoDB) to process user interactions through mobile applications.
- Created systems to benchmark cross-platform application performance (Apache Cordova stack) across various Android and iOS devices.

<u>3D Printer Technician</u> (May 2017 – December 2017) iCREATE Maker Spaces – Stony Brook, NY

- Assembled and tested new 3D printers.
- Cataloged and maintained all 3D printing equipment and consumables.
- Taught introductory CAD to 3D print course.
- Developed internal and external usage/maintenance documentation for various 3D printer modules (both for staff and student use).
- Held biweekly (2x / wk) self-service 3D printing trainings for general members.
- Processed prints from staff and students through high volume 3D print queue for entire university.

<u>College and High School Tutor</u> (May 2013 – May 2017) Varsity Tutors – Stony Brook, NY and Tenafly, NJ

Math and science tutor for students of all ages (kindergarten through college), both online (Varsity Tutors online platform) and in-person.

<u>Meet & Greet Coordinator</u> (May 2013 – September 2016) Ardmore Language Schools – New York, NY

 Guided foreign language students through airports and coordinated their transportation to Ardmore Language School campuses.

Miscellaneous

- U.S. DoD Clearance Level Secret
- Theta Tau Professional Engineering Fraternity
- Eagle Rank

Skills

Soft

- Adaptable, quick learner
- · Can create clear, testable requirements
- Can write clear, concise documentation
- Agile development
- · Strong multi-tasking
- · Able to interface with customers
- Ownership mentality
- Strong mentor

Technical

- Python/C/C++
- NodeJS
- HTML5/CSS/JavaScript
- MongoDB
- Microsoft Office
- Linux/Unix
- Bash/PowerShell/Batch
- IBM Rational DOORS

Education

B.S. - Technological Systems Management